If a newborn baby
comes with complications, then it is very important for
us to have a cover to save their life.
If we talk about newborn baby, then
your double sum will be left for
maternity. If I talk about my recommendation, then at the
top I will give pricing
factor cover point of view in which please
understand you are newly married and you are about to be
newly married, so you have to assure that this is the
first challenge. Hello one,
welcome to Transforming 360. Today,
from the current learning of my personal life,
as I had promised for you, I will
introduce you briefly on maternity.
Which maternity plans are
available in our country, which companies
are available, with what good limits are they
covered, and what all is covered, we will
cover its details in the review video today. So
before starting the video, I would like to
introduce myself, my self Dheeraj
Mahajan, having 12 years of rich experience
in health insurance but  Still I also did a mistake that I want you should not carry
in your journey of health insurance. So let's start the video
[music]
so maternity that means is a very important factor for every newly
married couple and for those couples who are
extending their family, it is a
very important moment in life for
which our entire family
and especially our parents are
waiting for a long time that a new member will
come home and they will welcome him and everyone
wishes that the
duration of nine months and after that should be
positive and both the child and the mother should
remain safe but in today's time, along with the
medical facilities, the medical
expenses have also increased a lot. We will talk about the
important maternity products of every company,
so all the youngsters, all the youth, all the
newly married
couples, those who are about to be newly married couples,
so first of all I  Wish you a great
married life and I wish you would have a
prosperous journey shoulder to shoulder and
explore a good experience in the coming future and that you and your family
always remain happy and healthy, this is what I wish.
So today first of all we will talk about
this most important point, if we talk about
Star Woman Care Product Star Woman
Care Product can be a very good option from the maternity point of view.
What does it offer us,
if we talk about the basic sum insured, it starts from 5 lakhs
and the maximum sum insured
goes up to 1 crore. Now the limit of maternity,
this product offers us the highest sum
insured that means 1 crore at ₹ lakh,
below that between 75 lakhs to 50 lakhs, it
offers a limit of 75000, then 50000 and up to ₹ 5000.
But more important than this maternity is the
thing on which I would like to talk in detail.  It
is a new born baby
because the point of maternity is that
we know that it has this much package
and the approximate cost will be Rs. 10 lakh to Rs. 2
lakh depending upon the city you are in right
but if the newborn baby
comes with complications then it is very important for
us to have a cover to save the life
that is new born baby and
new born baby cover this product
offers us with a very good limit that means
whatever is our basic sum insured
for example if my sum insured
is Rs. 1 crore then 25% of the basic sum
insured for new born baby is available that means out of Rs.
1 crore, 25 lakh or 50 lakh,
that is Rs. 12 lakh with us, similarly the sum keeps decreasing
so
you have to decide
how much cover we have to take for the newborn baby, from that point
of view from this angle you
can decide how much cover you should take so
this second thing is the newborn baby who
I felt that the most important factor
after my journey is that because I encourage each one of you,
so look at this point more,
instead of the limit of maternity, our newborn baby is
more important than the limit of hat,
so this product
offers us a very good limit for newborn,
thirdly a problem arises, many times it happens
that the child faces some problem in the womb itself,
which is called utero fetal surgery, that means
if there is any
problem in the stomach, then it is very important to see whether the treatment available for its correction is
available in our product or not, so in
this product there will be
actual cover on the actual, that
means up to some insurance cover will be there, it is a very
good thing, so do not miss this, if we
talk about another factor, that is IVF, because in
today's time, because
of stress and other things due to our eating habits, due to
our lifestyle, today
problems are arising in the womb and we are going for
IVF  As we move forward, this
product also covers IVF with a
certain limit and that limit is maximum ₹15
lakh and minimum is ₹15 lakh and the waiting
period for maternity is
only after one year if your sum insured is above 15 lakh,
if it is less than 15 lakh then your
waiting period for maternity is 2 years.
So this product also covers medicines
for our newborn baby
up to certain limits which is not that much important but
more important than vaccination where there is a
huge expense as I
told you from my incident, so every day that is the
bearing cost of ₹0000 minimum and it may
go on for the next 25 days and I wish that
my daughter comes back to me soon and
comes back in a healthy position and this is what you people would
also want, although you may never need it, I
wish everything goes well but this angle
We should not miss our health
insurance journey. Let us talk about the second product today.
That is Star Health Assure
Plan. This product also offers maternity cover,
which has a waiting period of 2 years.
We have a sum insured option from Rs 5 lakh to a
maximum of Rs 2 crore. The
maximum limit for a newborn baby under this product
is Rs 1 lakh. That means if my
sum insured is Rs 50 lakh and now that means up
to Rs 2 crore. So my maximum limit for a
newborn baby is Rs 1 lakh. If it is
less than Rs 1 lakh, then the company provides a limit of Rs 1 lakh.
One very good thing here is that
apart from maternity, the
waiting period for a newborn baby is only one
year. That means if the husband and wife were covered
and the wife had served the policy continuously for one year, and
if the delivery had taken place in the next year, then
in that situation
maternity would not have been covered because of that two-year
waiting period.  But the newborn baby becomes active, the
newborn baby cover will remain active,
God forbid that any such problem arises, then
you will have a solid backup of up to ₹ lakh,
so do not miss this, along with this
it also offers IVF for us, this
product also offers us for utero fetal surgeries,
whose limit is up to sum
insured, so this was the plan of Assure,
which we will compare now on the basis of
only maternity, in the next product we will talk about
NUPA's Aspire plan, Niva NUPA
Aspire plan, which has been recently
introduced by the company, also
offers maternity plan, the company
comes in four variants, of which I have already made a detailed video
on the channel, so if we
talk now, then the maternity limit in it
depends on the sum insured, the
highest sum insured in this policy is
one crore and the lowest sum insured is
₹ lakh, so under higher sum insured,
if my sum  If the sum insured is one crore, then
my maximum limit for maternity
is ₹ 5000. If my sum in short is ₹ 5
lakh, then my limit is 20000. If it is 50 lakh,
then that limit is 15000 and similarly it
reduces to 12000, 10000 and so on.
Also, the waiting period for
maternity is of three types, it
depends on the variants. If my
variant is Titanium Plus, then
my waiting period is only
nine months. If my variant is Diamond
Plus, then I will have to serve a waiting period of 24 months
for maternity and
if I talk about Gold Plus, then
I will have to serve an exact waiting period of 48 months.
You can opt for an optional cover within this product, which
means fast forward by paying premium
for four years. If you pay the premium for nine years, then
your  The maternity limit will be increased by
3 times, meaning that if the highest limit
is 25,000, you can avail up to 25,000,
and maternity will be covered after one month. However,
if we talk about newborn babies,
this product
also provides very good coverage for newborns. That is up to the
sum insured. This product
also offers IVF, surrogacy, and adoption.
We have maternity cover within its limit.
If we talk about adoption, the
maximum adoption cover prescribed by the government will be
covered within that limit. This is also
a decent option because if we talk about it, there
is not a very high limit, but yes, the main thing is that newborn
babies are covered up to the sum insured.
So this is a very positive thing here. Next, let's talk about EIG's Medicare Premier plan, which covers maternity by not paying extra premium.  The
waiting period is
4 years and the highest sum insured that
this product offers us is 3
crores. The maximum sum insured is 3 crores, 2 crores, 1
crore, 75 lakhs, 50 lakhs, 25 lakhs, 20
lakhs. These kinds of options are available in this
AAG medicate premium. The maternity
limit in this is on the screen in front of you. The
highest limit is if you are blessed
with a sweet baby girl, then the maximum
limit you will get will be 120000. If you are
blessed with a baby boy, then your maximum limit will be
₹1 lakh. It all depends on
your sum shot, as you can
see on the screen in front of you. The
newborn baby in this product does
not come with immediate cover, which is a
bad part. After 90 days, you
can add your newborn up to the sum insured.
If he is medically eligible, then
so new  From the birth point of view,
this product is weak. If we
look at another positive side of this product, then the
positive side is that if for example, the
family size was two adults plus two children
and the age of your
children is already around 20 years or
25 years, and in future, if they have already
invested 3 years, 2 years or 4 years in this product and in future, when they
move to their family and carry their policy, then there will be
no waiting period for maternity on them. This is a very
positive point. So next, let's talk
about ICAC Lombard's newly launched product Health Advantage Apex.
This product offers us a maternity plan in
which the maximum sum insured is 3 crore
and the minimum sum insured is 5 lakh. The
maternity limit that the company offers us here is
10 percent of the sum insured and
maximum up to ₹1 lakh. If we
talk about a newborn baby, then your double sum will be
insured.  For example,
if your maternity limit is ₹1 lakh,
then your newborn baby will be covered for ₹2 lakh.
If your maternity limit is ₹50,000 and
your sum insured is ₹1 lakh, then your
maximum newborn baby limit will be
covered only for ₹1 lakh. If we talk about
IVF, surrogacy or adoption, then this
product does not offer us at all.
If we pay three years' premium together
and there is a case of post-delivery surrogacy, then
this product covers complications up to 3 years, which is a good
thing. Talking about pricing, the
pricing of this product is also quite
reasonable. The next product which we are going to cover
is the
reliance.in plan, in which the maximum
sum limit is
₹1 lakh from the maternity point of view and the minimum is ₹1 lakh.
Both of these are optional and the minimum waiting
period is one year and the maximum is
two years.  It is optional, you can reduce it.
If we talk about a newborn baby, then the maximum
limit offered by the company covers only ₹1
lakh. At this point, the
product becomes a little weak and the pricing
factor also increases a bit. So, if we
talk about other things like IVF, surrogacy or
adoption, then this product does not offer us these things. The
next product we will talk about
is Bajaj Alis Health Care, in
which the basic sum insured starts from ₹5 lakh
and the maximum we get in this policy is ₹
5 crore. That means ₹5 crore. The maximum
maternity limit in this product is
₹1 lakh, below that it is ₹75,000 and
then ₹0,000. If we talk about the maternity waiting
period, then the waiting period is 36 months
in this product. This can be
reduced to 24 months
if we pay the premium for 3 or 2 years
together. IVF is a product.
This product does not cover surrogacy or adoption.
One of the most important factors
that we would like to see in this product
is the new born baby, which is
also the most important from the maternity point of view. So,
this product gives us a very good
limit in that. If my sum in shot is 50 lakhs
and above, then the maximum sum in shot that I will get
for the new born from day one would be
15 lakhs, which is good enough. If
my sum in shot is less than that, if my sum in shot is up to ₹ 1 lakh, then
my maximum limit will be
₹ 1 lakh, and it will keep reducing to
₹ 1 lakh, and the minimum limit is ₹ 1
lakh. So, according to the sum in shot, we have to
see that we go towards the high sum in shot and
opt for the right option. This product does
not offer adoption. This product does not offer adoption.
Now, what is surrogacy? I am
using this word again and again. Surrogacy
means that today someone  And in a
way, they take the womb on rent and see the scope for their child in it.
If in that case,
in case of surrogacy, after maternity, after
delivery, if any complication arises even after that, then
this product covers up to some certain limit.
So lastly, we will talk about
Aditya Birla's Active, in which the
minimum limit of maternity is 0000
in case of normal delivery and the maximum limit in C-section is
60000. And one
negative point that comes here is that the
newborn baby
comes within your within maternity limit, so
I will not recommend this product to you at all.
Aditya Birla gives us an additional option,
that is VIP Plus. There are
two types of offers in VIP Plus, one
comes with domestic cover and the other
comes with abroad cover. There is an option in abroad cover also
whether you want to include USA, Canada or
exclude it, then there is a
premium difference between both. If
we talk about the cover, then in domestic  The
maximum limit for maternity is ₹1 lakh
and in international markets, the limit goes up to
₹1 lakh and in case of newborn babies too, the
same limit applies to maternity.
So, if I talk about my recommendation,
I will give the top priority from the pricing factor
cover point of view, in which four to five
factors are covered from the maternity point of view. So, the
first number I will give is Star Woman
Care with good pricing. If we
talk about price also, for two adults,
if someone is less than 35 years old and you belong to
any location pan India, then
your price is going to remain the same. So, a
sum of ₹1 crore will cost you ₹
9000 and here the three-year barrier has been removed, so
you can get maternity cover by paying in one year only.
But the recommendable one has a
good limit for newborn babies which goes up
to ₹1 lakh, up to ₹1
lakh, followed by surrogacy cover. Thirdly,
Aspire.  The plan of Niva Voopa is just because
of only one thing, the maternity limit is very low,
but the newborn baby which is covered is up to the
sum insured, so I will give it the third point third number.
Talking about Aspire fourth, Star
's Again Assure plan is again a good option
because it gives us the option after two
years when our maternity starts, but the
newborn baby becomes active after one year.
With certain limits
up to ₹1 lakh, but correction has to be done within the plan.
If any problem arises, then that is also
covered under it. IVF is also covered,
so definitely this product will also be a good
option for you. I will give the number to
Lila's Infinity plan, which has a
decent maternity limit, but
from the newborn baby's point of view, the product is weak,
so I wish you would have a great set of
choices. Please understand that you are newly married
and you are about to get married, so you have to
assure that this is the first challenge which  It is going to come in
front of you because I have seen such a
face, so I am bearing this problem and every day there is a
cost which is
associated by Rs. 0000 per day and I know and the
hospitalization duration may extend for
next 20 or 25 days, so you can calculate
how big a financial burden it becomes
and so I wish you take the right decision, if you
need any help in any way
then feel free to talk to me because definitely
after one experience I
have the possibility to give you better advice,
so I wish you all the best, please
share the video as much as possible, if you have
not subscribed to the channel then definitely share it
and keep encouraging us to
bring more effective and good solutions for you
so that your insurance journey
becomes transparent, all the best, thank you